calculatestuff.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Calculate Stuff, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We help protect you from overreaching government demands for your personal information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

### Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

Calculate Stuff (ABN: 19 495 268 956) is based in Australia. Our website calculatestuff.com offers free online calculators to a worldwide audience as well as a paid service that allows users to embed our calculators within their own websites.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use calculatestuff.com and any of our various subdomains such as de.calculatestuff.com or widgets.calculatestuff.com.

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our services, to communicate with you, or to make our services better. We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

#### Information You Provide to Us

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * **Basic Account Information:** We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for a CalculateStuff.com account to provide an email address–and that’s it.
  * **Site Information:** If you create a subscription for one of our widgets we ask for a licensed domain. This allows us to grant access to the content when viewed on your website.
  * **Communications With Us (Hi There!):** You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys or communicate with our us about a support question.

#### Information We Collect Automatically

We also collect some information automatically:

  * **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information whenever you use our services.
  * **Usage Information:** We collect information about your usage of our services. For example, we collect the last IP address that you logged in with and the number of views and calculations performed with your widgets.
  * **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our services from certain geographic regions.
  * **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. Calculate Stuff uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness and to deliver targeted ads. For more information about our use of cookies and other technologies for tracking, including how you can control the use of cookies, please see the section titled "Cookies" below.

#### Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may also get information about you from other sources. For example, if you create a paid subscription, PayPal will send us information about the transaction including your PayPal email address, PayPal account name and country of residence for tax purposes.

### How And Why We Use Information

#### Purposes for Using Information

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our services-for example, to set up and maintain your account, host your calculator widgets, or charge you for any of our paid services;
  * To further develop and improve our services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our services, which helps us improve our services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition--for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our services after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our services, protect the security of our services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of Calculate Stuff and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our services;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by Calculate Stuff and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on Calculate Stuff and our products; and
  * To personalize your experience using our services, provide content recommendations, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular calculator widget with us or have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

### Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account--for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or

(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or

(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or

(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information--for example, to provide and update our services, to improve our services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our services, and to personalize your experience; or

(5) You have given us your consent

### Sharing Information

#### How We Share Information

We do not sell our users’ private personal information. We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * **Third Party Vendors:** We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you. This group includes vendors that help us provide our services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, customer chat and email support services that help us communicate with you, those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), and those that help us understand and enhance our services (like analytics providers), who may need information about you in order to, for example, provide technical or other support services to you. We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them.
  * **Legal Requests:** We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
  * **To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:** We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Calculate Stuff, third parties, or the public at large.
  * **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that Calculate Stuff goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction.
  * **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our services and we may share a hashed version of your email address to facilitate customized ad campaigns on other platforms.
  * **Published Support Requests:** And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

### How Long We Keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it--which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information--and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we keep the web server logs that record information about a visitor to the website, such as the visitor’s IP address, browser type, and operating system, for approximately 30 days. We retain the logs for this period of time in order to, among other things, analyze traffic to the website and investigate issues if something goes wrong.

### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

### Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * **Limit the Information that You Provide:** If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features may not be accessible.
  * **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** At this time, Calculate Stuff does not respond to “do not track” signals. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using our website, with the drawback that certain features may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * **Close Your Account:** While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our services :( :( :( :(, [please contact us to request closure of your CalculateStuff.com account](mailto:support@calculatestuff.com). Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above--for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

    * Request access to your personal data;
    * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
    * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
    * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
    * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us. EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please [contact us](mailto:support@calculatestuff.com). 

### Other Things You Should Know (Keep Reading!)

#### Transferring Information

Because Calculate Stuff's services are offered worldwide, the information about you that we process when you use the services in the EU may be used, stored, and/or accessed by individuals operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us, other members of our group of companies, or third party data processors. This is required for the purposes listed in the How and Why We Use Information section above. When providing information about you to entities outside the EEA, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy as required by applicable law. These measures include:

    * In the case of US based entities, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them, or ensuring they have signed up to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome); or
    * In the case of entities based in other countries outside the EEA, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them.

You can ask us for more information about the steps we take to protect your personal information when transferring it from the EU.

### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data, stored in text files, that are stored on your computer or other device when websites are loaded in a browser. They are widely used to ‘remember’ you and your preferences, either for a single visit (through a ’session cookie’) or for multiple repeat visits (using a ‘persistent cookie’). They ensure a consistent and efficient experience for visitors, and perform essential functions such as allowing users to register and remain logged in. Cookies may be set by the site that you are visiting (known as ‘first party cookies’), or by other websites who serve up content on that site (‘third party cookies’).

Calculate Stuff uses ‘first party cookies’ to identify and track visitors, their usage of our services, and their website access preferences. We also use external ad and analytics services which require ‘third party cookies’ be set. For further information on these services please see "Ads and Analytics services Provided by Others" below.

### Controlling cookies

Visitors may wish to restrict the use of cookies, or completely prevent them from being set. Most browsers provide for ways to control cookie behaviour such as the length of time they are stored – either through built-in functionality or by utilizing third party plugins.

To find out more on how to manage and delete cookies, visit [aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/). For more details on advertising cookies, and how to manage them, visit [youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (EU based), or [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) (US based).

It’s important to note that restricting or [disabling](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7HrnWC8zBcE) the use of cookies can limit the functionality of sites, or prevent them from working correctly at all.

### Web beacons and other tracking technologies

Both websites and HTML e-mails may also contain other tracking technologies such as ‘web beacons’. These are typically small transparent images that provide us with statistics, for similar purposes as cookies. They are often used in conjunction with cookies, though they are not stored on your computer in the same way. As a result, if you disable cookies, the web beacons may still load, but their functionality will be restricted.

### Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others

Ads appearing on any of our services may be delivered by advertising networks. Other parties may also provide analytics services via our website. These ad networks and analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our website and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by Calculate Stuff and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

#### Ads

Any advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. As mentioned above, any tracking or data collection done by Google or their advertising partners through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to their own privacy policies. Users may opt out of Google’s personalised advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) (<https://www.google.com/settings/ads>).

**A special note for EEA users:** we only show you non-personalised ads, these ads are selected based on the content you are currently viewing rather than your interests or prior behaviour.

#### Analytics

Calculate Stuff uses Google Analytics to collect information about how our services are used and interacted with. This information is de-identified, your IP address is anonymised and the “Demographics and Interest” features offered by Google Analytics are disabled.

For information on how this data is collected and processed please see ["How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps"](https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners)

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Calculate Stuff may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. We encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to the Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the last updated date below, and, in some cases, we may provide additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage, or sending you a notification through email). Your further use of our services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy. That’s it! Thanks for reading.

**Last Updated May 25, 2018**
